# **Haejin Kim**

(805) 252-6937 | haejin kim@bren.ucsb.edu | Webpage | GitHub | LinkedIn | Santa Barbara, CA

#### **PROFILE STATEMENT**

With over six years of experience in portfolio data analysis and management across both private and public sectors, I have refined my data management skills in daily pipeline data monitoring and organization, adept at handling environmental data as well. Additionally, I have provided significant insights to senior management through data review.

#### **EDUCATION**

## **Master of Environmental Data Science** (6/2024)

#### Bren School of Environmental Science & Management – University of California, Santa Barbara (UCSB)

<u>Highlighted Coursework</u>: Statistics for Environmental Data Science, Geospatial Analysis & Remote Sensing, Databases and Data Management, Machine Learning in Environmental Science, Data Cleaning, Text Analyst, Carbon Counting

<u>Highlighted Project</u>: Assessing the Impact of Supply-Side Policies on Oil Extraction, Emissions, Health, and Employment in California (SB 1137)

## **Bachelor of Science in Material Science and Engineering** (12/2012)

#### Cornell University, Ithaca, NY

<u>Highlighted Project</u>: Sol-Gel Synthesis and Testing of Li<sub>1+x</sub>NiMg<sub>x</sub>O<sub>2(1+x)</sub> Cathode Material for Li Ion Batteries

# Master of Science in Sustainability Science (Withdraw, 06/2022)

#### Columbia University, Ithaca, NY

Highlighted Coursework: Climate Change Law and Policy in Columbia Law School

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

Hankook Tire, Seoul, Korea (1/2014–6/2021)

### **Project Management and Data Analyst** (8/2016–6/2021)

- Developed a new real-time portfolio monitoring system using SQL, continuously refining portfolio data to improve data quality and accuracy.
- Created a predictive cost model for future profit by leveraging forecasting data of raw materials, technology development, and sales data through SQL.
- Conducted bi-weekly reporting of updated or new projects to the head manager and facilitated dissemination of decisions to relevant colleagues.

#### **Entry Material Research and Development Manager** (1/2014–7/2016)

- Nurtured ongoing relationships with vendors (entities) and worked to minimize issues.
- Monitored all aspects of vendor work and ensured that contract deadlines were met and resolved vendor (entities) disputes in a timely and professional manner.

#### Green Climate Fund (GCF), Songdo, Korea (7/2022–7/2023)

## Intern (Pipeline Management), Division of Mitigation and Adaptation (1/2023–7/2023)

- Coordinated and updated timelines for adjusting pre-approval pipeline projects, liaising with other divisions prior to board meetings.
- Assisted in collecting, verifying, analyzing, and disseminating data for reports, presentations, and other knowledge products related to project pipeline management.
- Regularly monitored IPMS and proposed new data collection workflows as needed.
- Provided analytical support for publications for the 34 and 35th board meeting using Tableau.
- Reviewed the concept note, aligned with the GCF's objectives, policies and investment criteria as Secretariat.

Intern (Accreditation Entity and Relation Unit), Division of Country Program (7/2022–12/2022)

- Reviewed entity applications and participated in the accreditation process.
- Supported the 33rd board meeting and facilitated communication with entities and other divisions.

### World Wildlife Fund (WWF), Seoul, Korea

## Senior Officer, Climate & Energy Team (7/2021–12/2021)

- Collaborated with WWF partners, primarily initiated in environmental projects.
- Supported to understand SBTi and TCFD for electronic and insurance company to join this program for climate action and derive the RE100.
- Supported in organizing the Climate Action Conference, including inviting guests and benefactors, and working with event agencies.
- Composed and delivered the WWF statement for COP26 to four Korean government departments, including the Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Environment, Finance, and Economy

#### **SKILLS AND ADDITIONAL EXPERIENCE**

Languages: Korean (native), Japanese (JLPT 3N)

Computer Skill: Python, R, Q/ArcGIS, MATLAB, C++, MS Office, SQL (SAP ERP system), Tableau, GitHub